Latin America later we could see the list of the eight and from the main
拉丁美洲稍后我们可以看到八个国家的名单以及主要的
three aspect of the pathway. The first is the developer education. In the emerging
路径的三个方面。首先是开发者教育。在新兴的
region we're gonna have the developer education in each region to educate the
我们将在每个地区进行开发者教育，以教育
developers and to how could they use Ethereum to build the
开发人员以及他们如何使用以太坊来构建
native applications and also how could they use AI knowledge or AI
原生应用程序以及他们如何使用人工智能知识或人工智能
tools or genetics even if you are not a developer, you are a product manager, you
工具或遗传学，即使你不是开发人员，你是产品经理，你
are an operation, you are a marketing and you could use the AI agent or use the AI
是运营，你是营销，你可以使用人工智能代理或使用人工智能
tools to do your own business, to create your own project. And the second is
开展自己的业务、创建自己的项目的工具。第二个是
the hack zone and the selection track. In each region we're gonna also have the
黑客区和选择轨道。在每个地区我们也会有
offline hack zone and online hack zone to select the builders around the world
线下黑客专区和线上黑客专区，甄选全球建设者
and send them to the later, you know, about October in pop-up cities to
然后将它们发送到稍后，你知道的，大约十月份的弹出城市
accelerate them and gonna have the chance to introduce your project
加速他们并将有机会介绍您的项目
more during the dive count in Mumbai. And also in the region just like
孟买的潜水计数期间还有更多。而且在该地区就像
Australia there are lots of the good researchers there and we're also gonna
澳大利亚那里有很多优秀的研究人员，我们也会
to collaborate with the universities to have the research workshops to
与大学合作举办研究研讨会
discover more about the frontier research in each aspect. So for the whole
了解更多各个方面的前沿研究。所以对于整体来说
year's timeline you could see that today is the official launch of the EHE this
今年的时间表你可以看到今天是 EHE 的正式发布
year's plan and from May to September they're gonna be just as we said is
今年的计划，从五月到九月，它们会像我们说的那样
there is a global builder applications and the builders initiatives from in
有一个全球建筑商应用程序和来自中国的建筑商倡议
Africa, Australia, Latin America and the Indian and in about this gonna be
非洲、澳大利亚、拉丁美洲和印度，在这方面
happen in half a year and in about October they are gonna be in Shanghai
半年后发生，大约十月他们将在上海
in 2026 and welcome all of you to apply for it, to join the pop-up cities, to
2026年欢迎大家申请，加入快闪城市，
find your co-founders there, to meet with the VCs, to exchange with
在那里找到你的联合创始人，与风险投资家会面，与他们交流
the directly information from the founders who have been succeed and we
来自成功创始人和我们的直接信息
will help all of you to do our best to support. And for Shanghai this year
将帮助大家尽最大努力支持。而今年的上海
gonna be happen in October in Hong Kong and some weeks in Shenzhen and for the
将于十月在香港举行，几周后在深圳举行
last week of Shanghai this year gonna be hosting Mumbai because of this
今年的上海上周将举办孟买比赛
year's dive count which is the largest developer conference in Eastern
今年的潜水计数是东部最大的开发者大会
ecosystem gonna be happen in Mumbai in November. So the last week of this year's
生态系统将于 11 月在孟买发生。那么今年的最后一周
Shanghai is in Mumbai and we hope that every of the builders around the world
上海在孟买，希望全世界的建设者
could join what's happen in Mumbai and have the chance to present to show the
可以参加孟买发生的事情，并有机会展示
broader Eastern ecosystem what you are doing. So here is the whole planted cities
更广泛的东部生态系统你正在做什么。这是整个种植城市
in each region. We're gonna be go to Kenya, Ghana, Bolivia, Australia, New Zealand,
在每个地区。我们要去肯尼亚、加纳、玻利维亚、澳大利亚、新西兰、
Indian and come join us this trip, this explore together. Okay I think it's a
印度人和我们一起来参加这次旅行，一起探索。好吧，我认为这是一个
whole introduction for EAG. For last ten years we have built lots of the
EAG 的完整介绍。在过去的十年里，我们建造了许多
infrastructure. Last ten years is for infrastructure but next ten years is
基础设施。过去十年是基础设施建设，未来十年是
for applications. I think no matter you are the developer, you are everyone who
用于应用程序。我想无论你是开发者，你都是每个人
want to build on Ethereum or you have already have the institutions project on
想要在以太坊上构建或者您已经有机构项目
the Ethereum. Let's join EAG together to accelerating the real world impact among
以太坊。让我们一起加入 EAG，加速对现实世界的影响
the Ethereum application ecosystem. Thank you. Thank you Audrey. As we are heading
以太坊应用生态系统。谢谢。谢谢你奥黛丽。当我们前进时
into the later half of the event I'd like to welcome those who have just
在活动的后半部分，我想对那些刚刚参加的人表示欢迎
joined us at Ethereum application gathering. Let's start chapter 3
加入我们的以太坊应用聚会。让我们开始第3章
application tracks, real world directions. We will have a deep dive into emerging
应用程序轨道，现实世界的方向。我们将深入探讨新兴市场
applications directions where Ethereum can create real projects. Next we have
以太坊可以创建真实项目的应用程序方向。接下来我们有
YQ founder of Outlayer sharing his insight on agentic engineering on
Outlayer 创始人 YQ 分享代理工程见解
Ethereum challenges and solutions. Please welcome YQ. Yeah great to see
以太坊的挑战和解决方案。欢迎YQ。是的，很高兴看到
everyone. So YQ here founder of Outlayer. So today I'm going to share sort of the
每个人。所以YQ这里是Outlayer的创始人。所以今天我要分享的是
progress and also updates we've been working on on this agentic engineering
我们一直致力于这项代理工程的进展和更新
on Ethereum in general. And some of you may recognize like sort of the stuff I
一般而言，在以太坊上。你们中的一些人可能会认出类似我的东西
was working on like since early this year. So I've been working on project
从今年年初开始就一直在努力。所以我一直在做项目
called Ease 2030. Basically I use like different models to do this agentic
称为 Ease 2030。基本上我使用不同的模型来完成此代理
engineering to really code sort of the all the new EIPs and the features for
工程真正编码所有新的 EIP 和功能
the Ethereum for the next five years roadmap. And it actually came from one of
以太坊未来五年路线图。它实际上来自其中之一
the batch I had with Vitalik. So we like we batched I sort of like whether I can
我和 Vitalik 的那一批。所以我们喜欢分批，我有点喜欢我是否可以
really code like sort of the the Ethereum roadmap for the next five years
真正的代码类似于以太坊未来五年的路线图
in a week. And before this sort of this year Chinese New Year I really use like
一周内。在今年的农历新年之前，我真的很喜欢
this cloud code and also this codex to do this kind of a challenge within a
这个云代码和这个法典可以在一个
week. Basically code as you can see right are tons of lines, code and to
星期。基本上，正如您所看到的，代码中有大量的行、代码和
implement brand new Ethereum client for both execution client and also these
为执行客户端和这些客户端实施全新的以太坊客户端
consensus client to achieve sort of the all the new features and the EIPs for
共识客户端实现了所有新功能和 EIP 的排序
Ethereum for the next few years. And you can check out the website it's
未来几年的以太坊。你可以查看它的网站
eth2030.com and you can see it has all the details on the all the EIP and
eth2030.com，您可以看到它包含所有 EIP 和
features for the next few years. The cool things is not just about like okay we
未来几年的特点。酷的事情不仅仅是像好吧我们
can really web code or do this agentic engineering to code everything for
真的可以进行网络编码或进行代理工程来编码所有内容
Ethereum core protocol in a week. We have a lot of license and the learnings
以太坊核心协议一周内完成。我们有很多许可和经验教训
from this. As I mentioned here right we spent almost a week and to code it but
由此。正如我在这里提到的，我们花了将近一周的时间来编写它，但是
after that we spent another month to really fix all the bugs and do all the
之后我们又花了一个月的时间来真正修复所有的错误并完成所有的工作
debugging and to make it work and to have the sort of the DevNet. And also
调试并使其正常工作并拥有 DevNet 之类的东西。还有
based on our experience we also trying to figure out okay beyond these sort of
根据我们的经验，我们还试图找出超越这些的方法
coding agents and also this engineering stuff right what kind of agents we need
编码代理以及工程材料我们需要什么样的代理
Ethereum and for these agents like what kind of new features and tools we need
以太坊以及对于这些代理来说我们需要什么样的新功能和工具
to develop to support them. And beyond that based on the experience and
发展来支持他们。除此之外，基于经验和
learnings and also the challenges we face we also customize a bunch of these
学习以及我们面临的挑战，我们还定制了其中的一些
tools like this Austin mentioned earlier like sort of the skills and we further
像奥斯汀之前提到的类似技能的工具，我们进一步
fine-tune some models to make it like we can have a better developer experience
微调一些模型，让我们能够拥有更好的开发者体验
and ship faster with all these new tools we develop and later I can share more
使用我们开发的所有这些新工具更快地发货，稍后我可以分享更多
about it. And in the future if you really want to redo this kind of East 2030 or
关于它。未来如果你真的想重做这种东方2030或者
similar kind of very hardcore engineering on Ethereum you can just
以太坊上类似的非常硬核的工程你可以
reuse these tools to like make your work ten times faster. As I just mentioned
重复使用这些工具可以使您的工作速度提高十倍。正如我刚才提到的
right all the things that came from this batch I was Vitalik and and basically we
是的，这批产品中的所有东西我都是 Vitalik，基本上我们
tried to basically work on it day and night for six or seven days and to
试图基本上日以继夜地工作六七天，并
implement the Ethereum roadmap for the next five years it called a strong map
实施未来五年的以太坊路线图，这被称为强大的地图
and it has a lot of brand new features as you can see right it has features
它有很多全新的功能，正如你所看到的，它有功能
about its native account abstraction and also different this kind of ZK features
关于其本机帐户抽象以及这种 ZK 的不同功能
ZKVM and beyond that it also includes some of the post quantum cryptography to
ZKVM 及其他，它还包括一些后量子密码学
protect the entire particle against like sort of these quantum computer attacks.
保护整个粒子免受类似量子计算机的攻击。
It has I think over like tons of these EIPs and some of them are public and
我考虑过很多这样的 EIP，其中一些是公开的，
some but some of them are still under like sort of discussion phase so you
有些，但其中一些仍处于讨论阶段，所以你
won't really have a lot of information on like sort of the website. And if you
在类似的网站上实际上不会有很多信息。如果你
look at like sort of the the codebase we developed for these brand new Ethereum
看看我们为这些全新的以太坊开发的代码库
roadmap you can see that the structure is pretty good it follows the the golden
路线图你可以看到结构非常好它遵循黄金
standard for a lot of these blockchain engineering and I at the same time we
许多区块链工程的标准，同时我们
all know that Ethereum has a different layers there's execution layer like
都知道以太坊有不同的层，有执行层，例如
this gold Ethereum and also this consensus layer like this lighthouse and
这个黄金以太坊还有像这个灯塔这样的共识层
some other ones. And the cool thing is I just to show you right like after the
其他一些。最酷的是我只是在
first week we have all the codebase and then we spend a month to really debug
第一周我们有了所有的代码库，然后我们花了一个月的时间进行真正的调试
all that sort of the issues we have. And if you got like okay some of the issue
我们遇到的所有此类问题。如果你对某些问题感到满意
is not about like like sort of the the coding aging problem it's really like
并不是像编码老化问题那样，它实际上是这样的
the complexity of deployment and also development of the Ethereum
以太坊部署和开发的复杂性
protocol is just a way to complicate it. For example if you want to set up
协议只是使其复杂化的一种方式。例如，如果您想设置
a damn net right you need proper tools to set up a bunch of nodes. We all know
一个该死的网络，你需要适当的工具来设置一堆节点。我们都知道
that these physical cloud and codecs they're good on this web 2
这些物理云和编解码器在这个网络上很有效 2
development like this new UI, new backend, CRUD. But when they face this
像新的 UI、新的后端、CRUD 等开发。但当他们面对这个
sort of very complex tasks and the very complicated protocol especially in this
非常复杂的任务和非常复杂的协议，尤其是在这个方面
distributed environment it's not that straightforward. Even we set up
分布式环境就没那么简单了。就连我们也设立了
this kind of environment with a bunch of developers you can see that it requires
这种有一群开发人员的环境你可以看到它需要
multiple nodes and you need have different configurations. You have the
多个节点，您需要有不同的配置。你有
consensus layer you also have the execution layer. So the coordination is
共识层还有执行层。所以协调就是
another problem. So these things are not like sort of in the public that's why
另一个问题。所以这些事情不像是在公众面前，这就是为什么
most of model don't really know this and that's sort of the thing we need to
大多数模型并不真正知道这一点，而这正是我们需要知道的
instruct and teach the models to understand. And beyond that as I mentioned
指导和教导模型理解。除此之外，正如我提到的
typical is pretty cool to create a bunch of these codebase. I believe a lot
创建一堆这样的代码库是非常酷的。我相信很多
of you already have the experience like writing this code with web coding or
你们中的一些人已经有过使用网络编码编写此代码的经验或
this agent engineering. At the beginning is pretty cool. Quickly we can like the
本代理工程。一开始还是很酷的。很快我们就可以喜欢
AI shape some code, shape the sort of the MVP. But when the codebase I mean the
AI 塑造了一些代码，塑造了 MVP 的类型。但是当代码库我的意思是
lines of code increase a lot and we start to figure out it's pretty difficult
代码行数增加了很多，我们开始发现这非常困难
to debug. So that's sort of echo to the point I mentioned right. We spent six
进行调试。这与我刚才提到的观点有些呼应。我们花了六
days building it but another like sort of a month to really debug it to make
构建它需要几天的时间，但真正调试它需要一个月的时间
the first DevNet working. And if you look at like sort of some of the
第一个 DevNet 正在运行。如果你看看类似的一些
learnings and challenges we are facing. So it basically is about like the scope
我们面临的经验教训和挑战。所以它的范围基本上是这样的
we can feed into the models. For example if it's just a single function fix or
我们可以将数据输入到模型中。例如，如果它只是一个单一的功能修复或
like feature, single feature implementation is fine. But even for a
与功能一样，单一功能实现也很好。但即使对于一个
single EIP implementation is okay. Typically like after the implementation
单个EIP实现就可以了。通常就像实施后一样
with a bunch of tasks it works perfectly. But once you cross multiple
与一堆任务它完美地工作。但一旦你跨越多个
functions and multiple EIPs and it start to sort of having a lot of problems. The
功能和多个 EIP，它开始出现很多问题。这
reason now we know that it's real about the context, the context management. For
现在我们知道上下文、上下文管理是真实存在的。为了
most of the models at that time, for example even for the Opals for
当时的大多数型号，例如 Opals
crowd, it only has like 20,000 this kind of a context. But right now it has
这样的人群，也就两万左右吧。但现在它已经
1 million. It probably mitigated the issues a little bit but in general it
100万。它可能会稍微缓解一些问题，但总的来说
couldn't really feed all these kind of tons of alliance code into this context.
无法真正将所有这些大量的联盟代码输入到此上下文中。
And for most of the time it couldn't make the correct decision either for
而且在大多数情况下，它也无法做出正确的决定
implementation or for debugging. So that's why as you can see right, with
实施或调试。这就是为什么如你所见，
small this kind of context like injected into these kind of models it
小这种上下文就像注入到这种模型中一样
becomes like not as efficient as if just for some simple functions or simple
变得不像仅仅对于一些简单的功能或简单的那样有效
tasks. And at the same time if you use a lot of this agentic and engineering
任务。同时如果你大量使用这种代理和工程
right, if you got like for most of time even we have proper test suites and also
是的，如果你大部分时间都喜欢，即使我们有适当的测试套件，而且
a lot of these integration tasks. But for most of time we can see that there's
很多这样的集成任务。但大多数时候我们可以看到
some silent failures. The model doesn't tell you but actually it tells, it works
一些无声的失败。该模型不会告诉您，但实际上它会告诉您，它有效
but there are some hidden bugs, hidden failure crashes and make it like not
但有一些隐藏的错误，隐藏的故障崩溃，让它变得像不像
really work as we expect. So that's a part like if we really want to make
确实如我们所期望的那样工作。所以这就是我们是否真的想做的一部分
something as well as we want, it's better like to really make all these kind of
一些我们想要的东西，最好是真正制作所有这些
failures and errors to make as a crash. At least the models can recognize and
导致崩溃的故障和错误。至少模型能够识别并
also human can recognize. Beyond that, during debugging we found hundreds of these
人类也能识别。除此之外，在调试过程中我们发现了数百个这样的
bugs and as I mentioned right, these bugs are basically hidden inside all
错误，正如我所提到的，这些错误基本上隐藏在所有
different places. Especially if it cross function, cross libraries and cross
不同的地方。特别是如果它跨功能、跨库和跨
EIPs, it's pretty tricky for the AI to figure out because like it doesn't have
EIP，人工智能很难弄清楚，因为它没有
enough context. And for a lot of these this kind of caveats, all these hidden
足够的背景。对于很多这样的警告，所有这些隐藏的
bugs actually is identified during our human testing and basically we roughly
实际上，错误是在我们的人类测试过程中发现的，基本上我们粗略地
know it will have some problems and in the end it really has the problems. And
知道它会出现一些问题，最终它确实出现了问题。和
beyond that, there's another thing we learned during this process that I we
除此之外，我们在这个过程中还学到了另一件事：
really need some sort of these, right now we call it like shared memory or like
确实需要某种东西，现在我们称之为共享内存之类的
some this kind of shared context because like you may not just run one
一些这种共享上下文，因为就像你可能不只是运行一个
agent, you may run multiple agents in different environments. So in that case
代理，您可以在不同的环境中运行多个代理。所以在那种情况下
we definitely need some files or these kind of shared memories
我们肯定需要一些文件或此类共享记忆
across all the different agents. And typically if you are using cloud code,
跨越所有不同的代理。通常，如果您使用云代码，
the cloud.md is the best. You can treat it as bugs and sometimes you
cloud.md 是最好的。您可以将其视为错误，有时您
can really treat it as a shared memory and a context. So in that case if you
可以真正将其视为共享记忆和上下文。所以在这种情况下如果你
pull some specific or explicit instructions in it, for most of the time
大多数时候，在其中提取一些具体或明确的指令
the coding agent will follow. For codecs it will be agent.md. That's why like
编码代理将跟随。对于编解码器，它将是agent.md。这就是为什么喜欢
granularly figure out if we have a specific file, we can call it memory or
详细地找出我们是否有一个特定的文件，我们可以将其称为内存或
sometimes external files, and we ask the coding agent to follow it. But for most
有时是外部文件，我们要求编码代理遵循它。但对于大多数人来说
of the time they don't really check. Even you write it specifically in the
有时他们并没有真正检查。即使你专门写在
document, but it doesn't check. But if you put it at this kind of cloud.md or
文件，但它不检查。但如果你把它放在这种 cloud.md 或
agents.md, typical these agents will check. And beyond that I also summarized
Agents.md，典型的这些代理会检查。除此之外我还总结了
a bunch of these rules and the learnings in general. As I mentioned, if
一堆这些规则和一般知识。正如我提到的，如果
you have a relatively complicated task or like sort of these kind of
你有一个相对复杂的任务或类似的任务
codebase, you spend probably 10% of the time on this development, but the other
代码库，你可能花费 10% 的时间在这个开发上，但是其他的
remaining time probably you just spend on the integration and also this
剩余的时间可能你只是花在集成上，还有这个
debugging. And beyond that as I mentioned, this autonomy of the agents
调试。除此之外，正如我提到的，代理人的自主权
and agent engineering sort of decrease when sort of the scope grows
当范围扩大时，代理工程就会减少
because the context doesn't have enough space to capture all this kind of
因为上下文没有足够的空间来捕获所有这些
knowledge. And at the same time if we are working on some areas basically
知识。同时如果我们基本上在某些领域开展工作
there's not enough public knowledge, but with a lot of domain knowledge, then we
没有足够的公共知识，但是有了很多领域知识，那么我们
will see that most of the time we will still be on the experts time. They spend
会发现大部分时间我们仍然处于专家时间。他们花费
time on debugging and help the AI to do the development and debugging. And in the
调试时间并帮助AI进行开发和调试。并且在
end I said another thing. If you are like sort of senior engineer, you will see
最后我说了另一件事。如果你像一位高级工程师，你会看到
that this AI can be 100 times amplified. But if for not a lot of knowledge you
这个AI可以放大100倍。但如果你没有太多的知识
want AI to be the magic, at that time you will see that the AI won't really help
想让AI成为魔法，到时候你就会发现AI并没有真正的帮助
you much because there's a lot of, it may also further introduce a lot of
你多多因为还有很多，可能还会进一步介绍很多
bugs. And beyond that as I also mentioned, apart from this East 2030, we
错误。除此之外，正如我也提到的，除了东方 2030 之外，我们
start to figure out, okay, beyond just doing this engineering for Ethereum
开始弄清楚，好吧，不仅仅是为以太坊做这个工程
core protocol, we probably want to see in the future its agentic era. So what kind
核心协议，我们可能希望在未来看到它的代理时代。那么什么样的
of things we need to support all the different agents. So one thing that I'm
我们需要支持所有不同的代理。所以我是一件事
not sure whether you know there's a standard called 8004. It basically helps
不确定您是否知道有一个名为 8004 的标准。它基本上有帮助
to register agents and also provide this reputation validation for different
注册代理并为不同的代理提供此声誉验证
agents to register on chain. And we built this called 8004 scan. And right now we
代理在链上注册。我们构建了这个称为 8004 扫描的程序。而现在我们
already index over 20 different chains including Ethereum base, BNB chain, and
已经索引了 20 多个不同的链，包括以太坊基础链、BNB 链和
even Solana. So the EFT team will deploy the same contracts on different
甚至索拉纳。所以EFT团队会在不同的地方部署相同的合约
chains and all the agents on different chains so they can register on this sort
链和不同链上的所有代理，以便他们可以在这种类型上注册
of 8004. And our 8004 scan will index all the agents with all
8004。我们的 8004 扫描将索引所有代理
different metrics and analytics. As you can see, right, for just three months we
不同的指标和分析。正如你所看到的，对吧，仅仅三个月我们
grew from like sort of this zero to over like sort of a hundred seventy
从大约零增长到大约一百七十
thousand agents on chain. And beyond that as I mentioned, right, it's not just a
链上千个代理。除此之外，正如我提到的，这不仅仅是一个
pure indexing or registration system for the on-chain agents. Actually we also
链上代理的纯粹索引或注册系统。其实我们也
have different ways to measure the quality of the agents. We regularly
有不同的方法来衡量代理商的质量。我们定期
capture like sort of their their their wallet data and also we test the
捕获他们的钱包数据，我们也测试
liveness of the different sort of agent to make sure like if there are some
不同类型代理的活跃度，以确保是否有一些
users or agent want to call them they are always online. And beyond that as
用户或代理想要打电话给他们，他们总是在线。除此之外，作为
I mentioned
我提到过